Billie Huggins Harrison papers, Inclusive: 1923-1997, undated, Bulk: 1943-1947, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Billie Huggins Harrison papers
Inclusive: 1923-1997, undated, Bulk: 1943-1947, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
3906
Harrison, Billie Huggins, 1926 - 2013
1 document box and 1 oversized box.
The Billie Huggins Harrison papers consist of scrapbooks, photographs, and college diplomas.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Average.
Biography/Profile
Billie Huggins Harrison, the daughter of G. W. Harrison and Emma Ruth Gibson, was born on 1926 May 24 in Temple, Texas. After graduating from Temple High School in 1943, Billie attended Temple Junior College (now named Temple College), where she received an associate’s degree. She also attended Baylor University and graduated in 1947 with a bachelor’s degree in business administration. While in school, Billie kept scrapbooks that provide insight into the life of a female student during the 1930s and 1940s.
Upon graduating from Baylor, Billie moved back to Temple and began a thirty-year career working in the administrative offices of the Olin E. Teague Veterans’ Medical Center. On 1949 November 20, Billie married Bill R. Harrison. Throughout their lives, as Billie worked at the VA hospital, Bill worked as a sales manager at various car dealerships. The couple, it appears, never had any children. Bill died on 1997 October 29. Billie lived another sixteen years and eventually died on 2013 December 28. Bill and Billie are buried at Bellwood Memorial Park in Temple.
Scope and Content
The Billie Huggins Harrison papers begin in 1923 and end in 1997. The Scrapbooks series is the largest in the collection and consists of two scrapbooks documenting Billie Huggins Harrison’s elementary, junior high, high school, and college years. The collection also contains photographs and Billie’s two diplomas from Baylor University.
Arrangement
No finding aid existed for the Billie Huggins Harrison papers prior to the creation of this one.
Currently, the Billie Huggins Harrison papers are arranged in three series: I. Scrapbooks, II. Photographic Material, III. Baylor Diplomas.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 3906. Acquired 2014-03-12
Related Resources
Related references
Dossman Funeral Home. “Billie Ruth Harrison.” Accessed 2014 May 21.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Baylor University -- Alumni and alumnae.; Baylor University -- History -- 20th century.; Baylor University -- Students.; Temple Junior College.
Places
Bell County (Tex.) -- History.
Subjects
Women -- Education (Higher) -- Texas.; Women -- Education -- United States -- History.
Genres
Diplomas.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Scrapbooks, 1932-1947, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Average.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains two scrapbooks documenting Billie Huggins Harrison’s elementary, junior high, high school, and college years.
  - Elementary, Junior High, and High School Years (1 of 2), 1932-1946, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Elementary, Junior High, and High School Years (2 of 2), 1932-1946, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - College Years (1 of 2), 1943-1947, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - College Years (2 of 2), 1943-1947, undated (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 4)
- Photographic Material, 1923-1945, undated; 2
  This series contains a photo album and two loose photographs.
  Index Terms
  Genres
  Photograph album; Photographic print
  - Service Station, 100 E Adams Ave, Temple, Texas, 1923 July 4 (Box 1 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - Photo Album, 1938-1945, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Photo Album: Loose Items, 1943-1945, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Baylor Diplomas, 1947, 1997; 3
  This series contains Billie Huggins Harrison’s two diplomas from Baylor University.
  - Bachelor of Business Administration, 1947 June 2 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Golden Anniversary Diploma, 1997 March 24 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Commencement Exercises Invitation, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 5)